<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
<channel>
  <title>Satoru Makate's blog</title>
  <link>https://satorumakate.com</link>
  <atom:link href="https://satorumakate.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
  <description>Insights, shizo rants, geek outs and things I find amusing.</description>
  <image>
    <url>https://satorumakate.com/favicon.png</url>
    <title>Satoru Makate</title>
    <link>https://satorumakate.com/</link>
  </image>
  <language>en-us</language>
  <lastBuildDate>
    Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:59:47 +0000
  </lastBuildDate>
  <ttl>1440</ttl>
  
  <item>
    <title>Natural binary tree visualization</title>
    <link>https://satorumakate.com/pages/blog/betterbinarytree.html</link>
    <description><![CDATA[
      <h1>Natural binary tree visualization</h1>
      <p>
        There are tons of binary tree algorithm scripts out there. We love binary trees. 
        They are a classic introduction to recursion in programming, capable of a unique 
        problem solving ability. When it comes down to visualising binary trees, a simple 
        diagram will work for educational purposes. But what about other purposes? <br>
        When I googled binary trees I would get something like this:
      </p>
      <img src="https://satorumakate.com/assets/simple_binary_tree.webp" alt="Simple binary tree">
      <p>
        When you look into some trees that were actually generated with code, you can find something like this:
      </p>
      <img src="https://satorumakate.com/assets/generative-binary-tree.jpg" alt="Generated binary tree">
      <p>
        Looks awesome, but it's so straight and unnatural. It's missing so much tree character. I want a binary tree to look like an actual tree.
        I've searched the web on a qusest to find the best looking binary tree out there..
        There were close to no binary trees that looked like actual trees. What a bummer.
      </p>
      <p>
        I wanted to fix that, so I introduced more random() into the generation, with some colors. Basically, I've made an 
        algorithm that will recursively draw circles while moving up, slightly changing directions and getting smaller over time.
        To add more unpredictability, I've added chances to the branch that it will split after a certain length.
        Also, after the ongoing branch reaches a certain length, there is a chance that it will grow a leaf.
        Here is the result:
      </p>
      <img src="https://satorumakate.com/assets/better-binary-tree.jpg" alt="Generated binary tree">
      <img src="https://satorumakate.com/assets/better-binary-tree2.jpg" alt="Generated binary tree">
      <img src="https://satorumakate.com/assets/better-binary-tree3.jpg" alt="Generated binary tree">
      <img src="https://satorumakate.com/assets/better-binary-tree4.jpg" alt="Generated binary tree">
      <img src="https://satorumakate.com/assets/better-binary-tree5.jpg" alt="Generated binary tree">
      <img src="https://satorumakate.com/assets/better-binary-tree6.jpg" alt="Generated binary tree">
      <p>
        Some come out better, some worse. All and all I'm really glad how the generator turned out. Took a while to find the sweetspot
        in the configuration.
      </p>
      <p>
        Every once in a while you get a stump ~
      </p>
      <img src="https://satorumakate.com/assets/better-binary-tree7.jpg" alt="Generated binary tree">
      <p>
        I've posted the full code on <a href="https://github.com/howlbones/binarytreeartgeneration" target="_blank">github</a>. The github code has a UI with
          different settings that you can play around with. <br>
          Btw, watching the leaves grow is very mesmerizing.
      </p>
    ]]></description>
    <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 16:59:47 +0000</pubDate>
    <guid>https://satorumakate.com/pages/blog/betterbinarytree.html</guid>
  </item>

</channel>
</rss>